William Robert Borysiak

Email - will.boz@icloud.com

Portfolio - https://www.willborysiak.com/ GitHub Repo - https://github.com/willborysiak LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/will-borysiak/

I'm currently a developer with over two year's experience using the Angular framework. In addition I have two years experience using React for many personal projects using various third party API's. I also have professional experience with .NET and C# alongside personal Python development.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Professional Experience

- Built a globally-used web application using components in the Angular framework.
- Contributed to a .NET API project that handles data between the UI and database.
- Developed a MS SQL Server database by writing queries, creating tables and adding data.
- Maintained a SASS library to ensure compliance with Sketch designs across the application.
- Managed UI data flow using a NgRx store for state management across components.
- Organised data using class-based inheritance with interfaces, models and viewmodels.
- Troubleshooted application issues with IDE debugging and Chrome DevTools.
- Authored unit tests using Jest for testing of components, models and services.
- Provided E2E testing with Cypress for multi-component functionality.
- Enhanced app performance and resolved circular dependencies using NX libraries.
- Streamlined code management using code reviews, Git and Azure DevOps.

Personal Projects

Spreche Deutsch

An educational application for learning German using NextJs, Python and Postgresql.

Strava Dashboard

An application that displays exercise data made using NextJs, Tailwind CSS and Strava.

Can I Calorie

An application that calculates caloric balance using Angular, RxJs and NgRx.

Portfolio

A portfolio website made using NextJs, Tailwind CSS and Contentful CMS.

Handcrafted By BarbaraRuth

A marketing website made using GatsbyJs, Graphql, Tailwind CSS and Contentful CMS.

WW2 European Map

An application that shows battles of WW2 made using HTML, SASS, Js and Webpack.

Technologies Used

❖ Front-End

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | TailwindCSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | Angular | React | Next.js | Gatsby.js | RxJs | NgRx | Nx | ESLint | Git | Webpack

Back-End

.NET 8 | C# | MS SQL | Python | FastAPI | PostgreSQL

Testing

Jest | Jasmine | Cypress | VS Code Debugger | Chrome DevTools | Postman

Development Tools

Visual Studio Code | Visual Studio | Git | Azure DevOps | OpenAl

EDUCATION

Mill Hill School and Sixth Form

Ripley, United Kingdom

GCSE and A-Level Studies

Sept 2011 - Sept 2014

- A-Levels BTEC Public Services (Distinction*), BTEC Applied Sciences (Distinction), Extended Project (C)
- 11 GCSEs A-C including English (B), Mathematics (C) & Science (A)

Online Web Development Courses

Self-Taught

•	Responsive Web Design	freeCodeCamp – Dec 2021
•	JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures	freeCodeCamp – Jan 2022
•	Modern JavaScript From The Beginning	Udemy - Feb 2022
•	The Complete JavaScript Course 2022	Udemy - Mar 2022
•	React The Complete Guide	Udemy - May 2022

Additional Qualifications

Various, United Kingdom

Professional Development

		Various
•	NVQ Level 3 – Personal Training	Feb 2017
•	NVQ Level 2 – Fitness Instructing	Dec 2015
•	NVQ Level 2 – Customer Sales	Feb 2018
•	Mental Health First Aider	March 2019
•	First Aid at Work w/ AED	April 2019
•	National Pool Plant Management Qualification	Aug 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apteco

Warwick, United Kingdom

Software Developer

September 2022 – Present

- Create and maintain a front end user interface using Angular and its component based architecture.
- Develop a .NET 8 API by managing controllers, services and DAO's used across the solution.
- Query and write to a Microsoft SQL Server database that provides the data for the .NET API.
- Write unit tests using Jest to test components, models and services in the projects.
- Write End-to-end tests using Cypress to test functionality across multiple projects in the Apteco ecosystem.
- Utilise various technologies in our workflow such as Git, DevOps pipelines and Docker containers.

 Collaborate with a wider team of developers, designers, testers, support staff, marketers and business executives to deliver internationally adopted software.

Derby Arena

Derby, United Kingdom

Personal Trainer / Health and Well-being Advisor

May 2018 - Present

- Creating individual exercise programmes for a range of clients varying in age, ability, and experience with a keen eye for detail.
- Conducting a wide variety of exercise classes to large groups of people ranging from spin to bootcamps.
- Create and maintain positive, professional, and trusting relationships with clients.
- Accurately record and analyse client biometrics results in accordance with data protection.
- Maintain an online presence through our social media channels such as website, in-house app, Facebook page etc.
- Ensure compliance with the retention strategy to keep clients for continued business.
- Working as a collective team with the cycling, hospitality, events and reception staff for day-to-day tasks and large-scale events.

Alfreton Leisure Centre

Alfreton, United Kingdom

Lifeguard Customer Sales Assistant August 2017 – May 2018 April 2017 – August 2017

- Working to a monthly sales target with daily KPIs such as calls, interactions and lead requirements.
- Having a robust lead generation system that involved outbound calls, community interaction and face to face tours.
- Closing sales on a variety of services and up-selling/cross-selling to hit income targets.
- Post-sale support given to clients with check-up calls and emphasis on referral generation.
- Creating effective marketing campaigns to generate interest and revenue for our facility.
- On-going professional training to ensure we are following the latest guidance from the governing bodies.

William Gregg VC Leisure Centre

Heanor, United Kingdom

Relief Duty Manager Lifeguard Feb 2016 – April 2017 Sept 2014 – April 2017

- Managing the operations of a multipurpose leisure centre with swimming pool, modern gym, sports hall and preschool creche.
- Being responsible for the handling of the cash in the building involving banking and documentation of our transactions.
- Delegating the daily tasks amongst the staff to ensure our service standards are always met and problems are dealt with in a timely manner.
- Motivating the team under heavy workload and taking ownership for the operations of the building.
- Ensuring health and safety is always adhered to especially given the potentially dangerous nature of a gym and swimming pool.

Jan 2014 - September 2020

- Policing the streets of Derbyshire with integrity and impartiality, delivering a high-quality service to the people of the county.
- Conducting investigations towards crimes and providing support to victims of those offences.
- Write statements, use police systems, and present evidence in court to support the justice system in the prosecution of offenders.
- Assisting at the scene of incidents to ensure safety and effective investigations.
- Staying up to date with the law and changes to policing guidelines, ongoing training was a signature part of the role.
- Being flexible with working hours if required to ensure that the constabulary was sufficiently staffed during peak times.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Skills

Customer Service Excellence

Demonstrated extensive experience across all customer service facets, from lead generation and sales to service delivery, ensuring a seamless customer journey.

Community Engagement

Proven ability to forge strong connections across diverse communities, leveraging my fitness and social networks to build rapport and inspire others.

Motivational Leadership

Highly motivated with a passion for inspiring and uplifting those around me, fostering a positive and dynamic work environment.

Rapport Building Expertise

Exceptional skills in establishing and nurturing relationships, honed through years of customer service experience.

Process Management

Proficient in understanding and managing complex processes, with a keen ability to see how different components work together for efficient operations.

• Team Collaboration

Effective team player with the versatility to both lead and follow, ensuring team objectives are met with excellence.

Interests

Athletics

Avid participant in running, cycling, and swimming, with extensive experience in competitive environments. This includes a longstanding membership in a competitive swim club achieving Midlands and regional level recognition.

Archery

Competent in both field and target archery with varying bow types (recurve, compound, crossbow).

Winter Sports

Enthusiastic skier and snowboarder, engaging in both sports for recreation and challenge.

Outdoor Activities

Passionate about the outdoors for both relaxation and physical exercise. Regular long distance runner in various locations around the Peak District. Keen hiker with many holidays to Wales and the European Alps for mountainous adventures.